Adedamola Adesina Adeagbo

in Adedamola A. Adeagbo 🔗 Portfolio

PROFILE

Experienced Data Analyst and Brand Strategist with 3 years of experience. Increased marketing ROI by 20% and brand awareness by 200% in 1 year. Developed automated report system, improving efficiency by 20% in 2 years. Enhanced strategy effectiveness by 25% in 14 months.

SKILLS

- Tableau
 Visualization
- Data Modelling
- Cross-functional Collaboration
- Power BI Visualization
- Data Analysis & Interpretation
- Critical Thinking
 & Problem Solving
- Microsoft Excel
- Statistical Knowledge
- Project Management
- SQL (SQL Server, MySQL)
- Dashboard Design & Development
- Data Entry

PROJECTS

Data Cleaning and Exploratory Analysis of a Global Electronics Retailer

May 2024

- Using **MySQL** to implement and Extract, Transform and Load (ETL) Process to pull data from the different platforms and consolidate it into a single database.
- Performed data cleaning using **MySQL** to improve data quality and exploratory analysis to generate datadriven insights.
- Created a dashboard on **Power BI** for data visualization and validation of generated results from SQL queries to present to stakeholders.

Sales & Marketing Data for Pharmaceutical

April 2024

Company 🛮

Virtual Client's Project

- Utilized MySQL to extract data from 6 different related tables from customer sales databases using JOIN and VIEW
- Transformed and filtered data by using aggregating and filtering function to improve reporting process
- Performed data cleaning and data manipulation using power query on Excel to ensure data validity.
- Created a dashboard on Tableau for data Visualization and to present actionable insights from the data

Customer Churn Rate Analysis 🗷

March 2024

Personal Project

- Transformed and processed client's data by using **Power Query** and **Excel** to ensure data completeness and validity.
- Created a dashboard with **Tableau** to help client compare between the churn rate, customer retention rate and customers who joined.
- Provided technical insights on how the client can fully utilize their data to determine where stronger marketing actions are required.
- Consulted with client to determine the best metrics to be displayed on final product.

Market Analysis & Insights on Survey

January 2024

Personal Project

- Transformed and filtered data by using aggregating and filtering function to improve reporting process
- Established a foundation for a data-driven decision-making approach, leading to more effective strategies and stronger business outcomes.
- Created interactive dashboards in **Tableau** to visually represent the data and make the findings more comprehensible.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst (Marketing & Research)

April 2022 – present

49thStreet Media

- Increased sales team efficiency by 20% through the development of an automated report generation system, streamlining sales reporting processes.
- Enhanced data accessibility and decision-making efficiency by 15% with intuitive Tableau & Power BI dashboards, leading to improved data-driven decision-making processes.
- Contributed to a 20% increase in marketing ROI by conducting extensive primary and secondary research on digital marketing strategies, ads marketing, and brand promotions, leading to improved marketing effectiveness.
- Worked closely with the IT team to troubleshoot and resolve data discrepancies, ensuring the accuracy and consistency of data used in analysis.
- Prepared detailed reports and presentations for business meetings, contributing to strategic decision-making.

Brand Strategist & Analyst

January 2022 – March 2023

Draft.co

- Achieved a 15% increase in content across social media platforms, resulting in expected growth and improved brand visibility.
- Identified and capitalized on 15% more opportunities through ongoing competitor analysis, leading to enhanced market position and strategic advantage.
- Enhanced strategy effectiveness by 25% through data-driven adjustments, utilizing Twitter and Instagram analytics tools, resulting in improved brand performance and engagement.
- Successfully generated a 200% increase in brand awareness over the span of one year.
- Crafted visually engaging and concise reports and presentations to effectively convey research findings to clients and internal stakeholders.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Mechanical Engineering

2014 – 2019 | Osun, Nigeria

Obafemi Awolowo University

CERTIFICATES

- Microsoft Power BI Developer (2024)
- Tableau Certified Developer (2023)
- Certified Data Analyst IBM (2022)
- SEO Fundamentals Google (2022)

COURSES

SQL for Data Science

May 2024

University of California

Python for Data Science, AI & Development $\ \ \Box$

November 2023